Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory02 Mss.B.B61.inventory02
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents B
  - Bloomfield, Leonard (Box 7)
    - see Boas, 1936 Mar. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 2
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 May 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 25; 1p
    - To Boas not in file, 1938 Mar. 11; 1p
    - enc. Reports on Comm. Res. in American Lang., 1938 Apr. 15; 7p
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 5; 1p
    - see FB to Kroeber, 1939 Jan. 5
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 May 15; 1p
    - Margin LB to Edel, 1939 July 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 May 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Aug. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Aug. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Sept. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Oct. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Dec. 12; 1p
    - Edel, B.C. -- to Cowan, J.M., 1942 Dec. 30
    - Allen, L. -- to LB, 1927 Apr. 29
    - Edel, Bertha -- from LB, 1939 July 13; 1p
    - Edel, Bertha -- from LB, 1943 Jan. 8
    - Edel, Bertha -- to LB, 1942 Dec. 30
    - Edel, Bertha -- to LB, 1943 Jan. 20
    - Edel, Bertha -- from LB, 1943 Jan. 21; 1p
    - Edel, Bertha -- to LB, 1943 Jan. 22
    - Kroeber, A.L. -- to LB, 1940 Jan. 25
    - Stechert, G.E. & Co. -- from LB, 1940 Nov. 4; 1p
    - Swadesh, M. -- to LB, 1937 Oct. 22
  - Bloxam, George W. (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1889 Oct. 28
    - To Boas, 1890 May 20
  - Bluestone, E.M. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 21; 1p
  - Blum, E.C. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 12; 1p
  - Blumensohn, J. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1932 June 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Nov. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 June 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 July 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 July 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 26; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 21; 7p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 16; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 26; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept 19; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 17; 1p
  - Blumenthal, George (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1927 May 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Sept 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Feb. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1927 Aug. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 8; 1p
  - Blumenthal, Walter Hart (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 26; 1p
  - B'nai B'rith Magazine (Box 8)
    See Grusd, Edward E.
  - Bo------? (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1936 May 19
  - Boardman, Helen M. (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 17; 3p
  - Boas, Emil L. (Box 8)
    - From Franz B., 1902 May 17
    - From Franz B., 1904 Mar. 16; 4p
    - From Franz B., 1904 Oct. 25; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Jan. 16and 1905 Apr. 11; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 May 8; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 June 2; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 June 22; 2p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Sept 21; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Sept 25; 2p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Oct. 7; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Oct. 18; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Oct. 24; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Oct. 27; 1p
    - see FB to Adams, E.D., 1905 Nov. 1; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Nov. 15; 2p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Nov. 21; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Nov. 29; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Dec. 12; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1905 Dec. 21; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Jan. 3; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Jan. 24; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Mar. 20; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Oct. 1; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Oct. 13; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1906 Dec. 13; 1p
      - see Butler, N.M., 1908 Nov. 10
    - From Franz B., 1909 Dec. 16; 1p
    - From Franz B., 1917 Apr. 11
    - From Franz B., 1920 Mar. 10; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Mar. 30
    - To Franz B., 1904 May 3; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 May 27
    - To Franz B., 1904 Oct. 21; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Nov. 7; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Nov. 16; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Nov. 21; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Nov. 30; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Nov.?; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Dec. 19; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Dec. 30; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1904 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Jan. 12; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Jan. 16, 1905 Jan. 21; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Jan. 24; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Feb. 7, Feb. 1; 1p
      - see margin, Bary, A. de, 1905 Feb. 2
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 2; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 4; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 11; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 14; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 14; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Apr. 6; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Apr. 7; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Apr. 15; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Apr. 26; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 May 12; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 May 29; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 June 1; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 June 5; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 June 14and June 19; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 June 30; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Aug. 10; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Aug. 19; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Sept 18; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Sept 19; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Sept 29; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Oct. 19; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Oct. 26; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Oct. 28; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Nov. 9; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Nov. 14; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Nov. 28; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Nov. 29; 2p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Dec. 14; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Dec. 15; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Dec. 28; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1905 Dec.?; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Jan. 16; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Jan. 22; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Jan. 26; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Feb. 1; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Feb. 2; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Feb. 19; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Mar. 1; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Mar. 5; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Mar. 16; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Mar. 26; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 May 7; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 June 14and May 28; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Oct. 2; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Oct. 3; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1906 Oct. 12; 1p
    - To Franz B., 1909 Dec. 17; 1p
    - Hapfel, J.C.G. -- to ELB, 1906 Jan. 13
    - Kahn, O.H. -- to ELB, 1905 Feb. 23
    - Lambert, S.W. -- to ELB, 1915 Feb. 26
    - Marshall, Lewis -- to ELB, 1906 Jan. 13
    - Presby, F.H. -- to ELB, 1906 Dec. 3; 1p
    - Skalweit, R.A. -- to ELB, 1905 Dec. 20
    - Villard, H.G. -- to ELB, 1905 Feb. 2
  - Boas, Ernst P. (Box 8)
    - See Boas, F., 1885 Jan. 18
    - From EPB to Benedict, R.F., 1943 Feb. 3; 1p
    - Bennet, Wm. S. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 22
    - Berg, A.A. -- to EPB, 1942, Dec. 22
    - Bissell, Frank -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 23
    - Black, A.D. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 28
    - Bridge, John -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 24
    - Butler, N.M. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 21
    - Cattell, J.M. -- to EPB, 1943 Mar. 3; 1p
    - Conklin, E.G. -- to EPB, 1943 Mar. 3; 1p
    - Davis, Michael M. -- EPB, 1942 Dec. 22
    - Dublin, L.I. -- M. EPB, 1942 Dec. 23
    - Flemming, Mark -- M. EPB, 1933 Oct. 17; 2p
    - Howson, Roger -- M. EPB, 1942 Dec. 23
    - Kroeber, A.L. -- M. EPB, 1943 Feb. 19
    - Kroeber, A.L. -- from EPB, 1943 Feb. 24; 1p
    - Lane, Robt. P. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 22
    - Liebowits, B. -- to, 1933 May 4
    - Liebowits, B. -- to, 1934 Oct.8
    - Leland, W.G. -- to EPB, 1934 Dec. 24
    - Linton, Ralph -- from EPB, 1943 Feb. 10; 1p
    - Riess, Bernard -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 29
    - Rosenfeld, Kurt -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 22
    - Sachs, B. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 22
    - Sager, Robt. -- to EPB, 1942 Dec. 24
    - Shapiro, Harry -- from EPB, 1943 Feb. 10; 1p
    - Stern, Bernhard -- to EPB, 1945 Oct. 24
  - Boas, FRANZ (Box 8)
    - "Under Arctic Circle", 1885 Jan. 18; 29p
    - Notes, 1889 Jan.
    - Telegram, Berlin, 1886 May 28
    - Telegram, Berlin, 1898 Dec. 2
    - Telegram, Berlin, 1898 Dec. 3
    - Telegram, Berlin, 1898 Feb. 16
    - Invites to meeting, 1899 Dec. 12
    - Invites to meeting, 1900 Mar. 14
    - Invites to meeting, 1903 Jan. 9
    - Invites to meeting, 1903 Nov. 5
    - Invites to meeting, 1903 Nov. 14
    - Invites to meeting, 1903 Nov. 27
    - Invites to meeting, 1903 Dec. 15
    - Organ. Bureau American Ethn., 1904; 10 p
    - Courses, European Uni., 1904; 16 p
    - Courses, European Uni., 1904 Jan. 18
    - Circular letter, 1904 Apr. 28
    - Germanistic Soc., 1904 May 7; 1p
    - Germanistic Soc., 1904 May 7
    - Anthrop. Courses, 1904 Summer; 2p
    - Anthrop. Courses, 1904 July 8
    - Anthrop. Courses, 1904 Nov. 3
    - Anthrop. Courses, 1904 Dec. 16
    - Re Boas, Emil L., 1905 Jan. 16; 1p
    - Receipt, Am. Mus. Na. Hist., 1905 Jan. 24
    - Receipt, Am. Mus. Na. Hist., 1905 Jan. 30
    - Receipt, Am. Mus. Na. Hist., 1905 Jan. 30
    - Receipt, Am. Mus. Na. Hist., 1905 Jan. 30
    - Receipt, Am. Mus. Na. Hist., 1905 Feb. 8
    - Germanistic Soc. of Am., 1905 Mar. 1
    - Germanistic Soc., 1905 Mar. 27; 1p
    - RE: Jesup, M.K., 1905 May 17
    - RE: Bumpus, H.C., 1905 May 17
    - Notes on Museum, 1905 May- Dec.
    - East Asiatic Commit., 1906 Jan. 2
    - Bill to P. Hermann, 1906 Feb. 7
    - RX Mervin, R.E., 1906 May 14
    - Re: Prof. Bumpus, 1906 May 25
    - Receipt, G.G. Heye, 1905 June 12
    - Circular letter, 1906 Sept. 24
    - Minutes, 1907 Jan. 11
    - Minutes, 1907 July 21 & 31
    - Re: R.H. Lourie, 1907 Oct. 16
    - To Sophie Boas, 1907 Oct. 19
    - Handbook, N. Am. Lang.
    - Jesup N. Pac. Expedition, '09 Mar. 11; 4p
    - Jesup N. Pac. Expedition, '09 Mar. 16; 3p
    - Obit., Wm. Jones, '09 May 5; 3p
    - Obit., Wm. Jones, '09 May 24
    - Obit., Wm. Jones, '09 May 25
    - Obit., Wm. Jones, '09 Nov. 8; 3p
    - RE: Dorsey, G.A., '09 Nov. 29; 1p
    - RE: Dorsey, G.A., '09 Dec. 15; 4p
    - Re Waterman, T.T., '09 Dec.?; 1p
    - Circular letter, '09 Dec.?; 2p
    - Re Mrs. Sophie Boas & Urbach, 1910 Jan. 5
    - Re Mrs. Sophie Boas & Urbach, 1910 Sept. 20; 3p
    - Circular letter, 1910 Nov. 26
    - Circular letter, 1910 Dec. 19
    - Receipt, H.E.Sargent, 1911 Jan. 14 & 12
    - To? (in Spanish), 27 Aug. 1911; 1p.
    - FB -- to Hewett, E.L., 1911 Nov. 13
    - Re Mason, J.A., 1911 Dec.?
    - Receipt, Leo Sternburg, 1912 Nov. 9
    - Receipt, Science Press, 1913 Feb. 1
    - Receipt, Science Press, 1913 Nov.?; 1p
    - Archaeology - Phillips Academy, 1913 Dec.?; 5p
    - Anthrop. - Porto Rico, 1913 Dec.?; 4p
    - School & Society, 1913 Dec.?; 1p
    - List of MSS & publications, 1913 Dec.?; 3p
    - Expenses - trip, Europe, 1913 July 10
    - Receipts - Mexico, 1914 Mar. 2; 4p
    - Notes, 1914 Nov. 2; 1p
    - Re Germany, 1915 June 4; 4p
    - To?, 1916 June 6; 2p
    - Typing receipt, 1916 June 9
    - List of books, 1916 Nov. 29
    - Resolution, intern. soc., 1916 Dec. 15; 3p.
    - Resolution, intern. soc., 1916 Dec.?; 1p
    - Report, Folk-lore Jour., 1916 Dec.?; 3p
    - List of names, 1916 Dec.?; 1p
    - Paper, problems of anthrop., 1916 Dec.?; 3p
    - Re Biology teaching, 1916 Dec.?; 1p
    - Re Ambassador Gerard, 1917 Feb. 8
    - Re Pres.'s stand, Germany, 1917 Feb. 9
    - Re E.H. Morris, 1917 Mar. 12
    - Immigration legislation, 1917 Apr. 14
    - See Anon, 1917 Apr.
    - Statement, 1917 Apr.?; 1p
    - To? in re Anthro. Dept., 1917 Sept. 14
    - Address, Barnard Coll., 1917 Nov.; 8p
    - Re Intern. Jour. Am. Ling., 1917 Dec.?; 2p
    - Re Am. Folk-lore Soc., 1918 Jan. 31; 2p
    - Salish dialects, 1918 Apr.?; 1p
    - Research Council, 1919 Jan. 17; 3p
    - The Nation: Colonies & Peace Conf., 1919 Feb. 15; 8p
    - Letter to The Nation, Oct. 16: Scientists as Spies, 1919 Dec. 20
    - Paper-draft, 1919 Dec.; 2p
    - Bill from Goldman, Sachs & Co., 1920 Sep. 1
    - Memorandum, 1920 Oct. 12; 1p
    - Open letter, 1920 Nov. 29; 3p
    - List of Germ. scien. insti., 1p
    - Statement in Germ., 1921 Oct.; 1p
    - RX of H.H. Roberts, 1923 Feb. 5; 1p
    - Re H. KC6nig's exploration plan, 1923 Mar. 22; 1p
    - Expense acct., field trip, Brit. Columbia, 1923 Nov. 4-Dec. 24
    - To Boardman, H.M., 1924 Nov. 10; 1p
    - Expense acct., 1924 Jan. 3-5
      - (see H.M. Adler, 1/21/25)
    - RX of M.J. Herskovits, 1925 Feb. 6; 1p
    - Open letter, 1925 Apr. 27; 1p
    - "Kultur u. Rasse" clippings (see Boas, F. to De Gruyter), 1925 Sep. 18
    - Open letter re Melville Jacobs, 1927 Mar. 9; 1p
    - Open letter, 1927 Apr. 28; 1p
    - Draft of announcement of grant - Ind. lang., 1927 June
    - Boas et al, 1927 July 23; 3p
    - Open letter re G. Herzog, 1927 Nov. 10; 1p
    - Open letter re G. Herzog, 2p
    - Report re: Irene Barnes for fellowship, 1928 Mar. 16; 1p
    - Anthropology, 1928 June; 3p
    - Open letter
      - re: M. Jacobs, N. Sahaptin gram., 1928 Oct. 10; 1p
      - ??, 1928 Dec. 18; 1p
      - Re Penck-Stiftung, 1928 Dec.
        (see Defaut, A.)
      - See Duggan, S.P. to Com. for Assis. lesser national. of U.S.S.R., Leningrad, 1928 Nov. 19
    - See Duggan, S.P. to Moe, H.A., 1928 Nov. 19
    - See Intern. Cong. of Linguists, certif., 1928 Dec.
    - See Intern. Cong. of Americanists, speech
    - Re Fortune, Reo, 1929 Mar. 18; 1p
    - Re Phinny, A., 1929 Mar. 18; 1p
    - RX E.M.Phelps thesis, 1929 May 14; 1p
    - Report, Racial & Soc. Diff., mental ability, 1929 May; 2p
    - Note re Bogoras, W.G., 1929 July 2; 1p
    - Re Adamson, T., 1929 Dec.; 1p
    - Re Bunzel, R.L., 1929 Dec.; 1p
    - List, Ind. languages, 1929 Dec.; 1p
    - List, instruments, etc. Phys. Anthrop. Lab., 1929 Dec.; 2p
    - Open letter re Deuel, T. attach. Goodchild, D., 1930 Feb. 15; 1p
    - Re R.F. Fortune, 1930 Mar. 18; 1p
    - Re F. DeLaguna's fellow., 1930 Mar. 18; 1p
    - RX of Mrs. Harkness, 1930 Apr. 17; 1p
    - Open letter
      - RE B. Rosinski, 1930 July 10; 1p
    - F.B. Bibliography, 1930 Dec.; 1p
    - Re Freyd, G., 1930 Dec.; 1p
    - Re Weltfish, G. to Bd. of Fellow. Bio. Sci., 1931 Jan. 1; 2p
    - ?, 1931 Jan. 3; 1p
    - ?, 1931 Jan. 14; 1p
    - See enc. BF to T.M. Durlach, Mrs. M.I., 1931 May 6
    - Sprachmischung u. Sprachentwicklungen
      - (see Kerkhof), 1931 May 27
    - See Psychol. Register, 1931 July
    - Open letter
      - Re R.F. Barton, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p
      - Re D.S. Fansler, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p
      - Re R.S. Wallis, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p
      - Re W.D. Wallis, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p
      - Re E.L. Walton, 1931 Nov. 22; 1p
    - ?, 1931 Nov. 25; 1p
    - Open letter
      - Re O. Klineberg, 1931 Dec. 3; 2p
    - Address on growth, 1931 Dec.; 7p
    - Open letter
      - Re Mary Lois Kissell, 1931 Dec.; 1p
    - Notgemeinschaft der deut. Wissenschaft, 1931 Dec.; 5p
    - Open letter
      - re C. van Voorhis, 1932 Apr. 14; 1p
      - re M. Mandelbaum, 1932 Aug. 19; 1p
    - Pledge, 1932 Nov. 22
    - Open letter
      - re J. de Angulo, 1932 Dec.; 1p
      - re M. Jacobs, 1932 Dec.; 1p
      - re F. de Laguna, 1932 Dec.; 1p
      - re S.S. Newman, 1932 Dec.; 1p
      - re M.J. Herskovits, 1933 Jan. 27; 2p
      - re W.Y.H. Beukes, 1933 July 5; 1p
    - See VC6lkischer Beobachter, 1933 Aug. 24
    - Open letter, 1933 Oct. 4; 1p
    - Open letter, 1933 Oct. 5; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re B.W. Aginsky, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
      - re E.G. Aginsky, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
      - re Harris, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
      - re Briffault, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
    - Displaced intellectuals in Germany, 1933 Dec.; 3p
    - Open letter
      - re Duk, 1933 Dec.; 1p
    - Re Effective combat of Hitlerism, 1933 Dec.; 3p
    - Open letter
      - re A. Lesser, 1933 Dec.; 1p
      - re Newman, 1933 Dec.; 2p
      - re C.F. Voegelin, 1933 Dec.; 1p
      - re Yampolsky, 1933 Dec.; 1p
    - Nazi propaganda, 1933 Dec.; 1p
    - Open letter, 1934 Jan. 9; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re A. Phinney, 1934 Feb. 23; 1p
    - Aryans & Non-Aryans enc. with Schwiderman, 1934 Mar. 5; 12p
    - Receipts, students' field trips, 1934 June 7; 1p
    - Receipts, students' field trips, 1934 July 10; 1p
    - Report on race question, 1934 Nov.; 1p
    - Open letter, 1934 Dec.
    - Report, 1934 Dec.
    - Notes
      - see M. Jacobs, 1935 Feb. 10
    - Open letter
      - cultural conditions on races (2 copies), 1935 June 30; 3p
    - Open letter
      - (2 sets), 1935 Aug. 27; 4p
    - Open Letter, 1935 Aug. 27; 3p
      (7 sets)
    - Open Letter, 1935 Oct. 8; 3p
    - Open Letter, 1935 Oct. 8; 4p
    - ?, 1935 Dec. 20; 3p
    - Open letter
      - re K. Rodenfeld, 1935 Dec.; 1p
    - ?, 1936 May 8; 1p
    - A study, existing records, Anthrop. Dept.; music, art, lit. of AmericanInd. enc. P. Fishman, 1936 Jan. 17; 3p
    - To Bogoras,W., 1936 27
    - Open letter re Reuben Caluza, 1936 Jan. 22; 1p
    - Open letter re Alfred Métraux, 1936 Jan. 28; 1p
    - Open letter re R.F. Fortune, 1936 Sep. 28; 1p
    - Form letter (2 copies), 1936 Dec. 2; 1p
      re a Soc. for American Ind. linguistics
      - co-signers: Bloomfield and Sapir
    - Paper, 1936 Dec.; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re R.W. Bryan, 1937 Feb. 4; 1p
      - re M. Scheerer, 1937 Feb. 4; 2p
    - See G.B. Pegram to Cabanellas, 1937 Feb. 11
    - Open letter
      - re Günter Wagner, 1937 Feb. 13; 1p
      - re Leonhard Adam, 1937 Mar. 11; 1p
    - Open letter
      - Sapir co-signed, 1937 Apr. 5; 1p
    - Open letter, 1937 Apr. 7; 2p
    - Open letter
      - enc. Am.Ind. lang. Committee agenda, 1937 Apr. 13; 1p
    - Open letter
      - see FB to M. Swadesh, 1937 May 12
    - Open letter
      - re E.C. Deloria, 1937 July 7; 1p
    - ?, 1937 Sept 4; 1p
    - 3 drafts, cable, appeal
      - re Santander, 1937 Sept
    - Draft of FB to E.A. Hooten with F.Osborn
      - co-signer, 1937 Oct. 18; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re Marcel Acier, 1937 Oct. 25; 1p
      - re A. Lesser, 1937 Nov. 30; 1p
    - See Faculty commit., aid to Spanish people, 1937 Dec. 8
    - Speech Faculty commit., aid to Spanish people
      - see FB to N.Y. Times City editor, enc., 1937 Dec. 9
    - enc. Proposal, 1937 Dec. 20; 1p
      studies, determin. population qualities, genetic & environment
    - Open letter, 1937 Dec.; 2p
    - Open letter
      - re Dyett and Dyett, 1937 Dec.; 1p
    - ?, 1937 Dec.; 1p
    - RX of E. Sapir for APS grant, 1937 Dec.; 1p
    - re populations, 1937 Dec.; 3p
    - Kultur u. Rasse
      - see FB to Gruyter, 1938 Jan. 14
    - Open letter
      - Harold C. Urey co-signed, 1938 Jan.; 1p
    - Open letter on culture & democracy, Spain, 1938 Jan.
    - see Spain - For replies and the 12 p. open letter
      - N.B. Adams
      - G.W. Allport
      - R.H. Bainton
      - L.T. Baker
      - J.U. Barlow
      - M.W. Beckwith
      - M.J. Benardete
      - R.F. Benedict
      - T.E. Benner
      - C.A. Berdahl
      - R.M. Binder
      - C.B. Bourland
      - L.R. Bradley
      - E.B. Burgum
      - R.A. Burns
      - F.A. Bushee
      - W.B. Cannon
      - J. Casalduero
      - R.D. Carmichael
      - A. Centeno
      - J.A. Centeno
      - R. Chambers
      - A.V. Churchill
      - A.M. Coe
      - M.R. Cohen
      - E.M. Collins
      - A.S. Coolidge
      - P.W.L. Cox
      - Ephraim Cross
      - J.F. Dashiell
      - Jerome Davis
      - John Dewey
      - Wm. E. Dodd
      - Robt. B. Downs
      - J.C. Egbert
      - E. Fahnestock
      - P.V. Fernandez
      - Louis Ginzberg
      - M. Gottschall
      - Frank P. Graham
      - Saml. L. Hamilton
      - G. McL. Harper
      - H.A. Heaton
      - Chas. Hodges
      - Franklin W. Johnson
      - J.L. Kandel
      - H. Keniston
      - Wm. H. Kilpatrick
      - F.C. Lathrop
      - L.A. Lawson
      - H.E. Luccock
      - R.S. Lynd
      - R.E. McNicoll
      - Jorge Manach
      - Max F. Meyer
      - Clyde R. Miller
      - Louie M. Miner
      - Gardner Murphy
      - J.H. Newlon
      - Geo. Norlin
      - H.A. Overstreet
      - J.R. Owre
      - B. Parker
      - R.J. Peebles
      - R.V. Peel
      - Ralph B. Perry
      - J.K. Polson
      - J.H. Randall Jr.
      - Rollo G. Reynolds
      - G. Salvemini
      - Edward Sapir
      - Geo. Sarton
      - W.C. Sayre
      - Robt. Schevia
      - M. Schlauch
      - G.C.L. Schuchard
      - Fred. L. Schuman
      - H.E. Sigerist
      - R.K. Speer
      - Leslie Spier
      - E.H. Sutherland
      - N.L. Torrey
      - K.H. Vanderford
      - Seth Wakeman
      - S.D. Warden?
      - David McA White
      - John Whyte
      - T. Wolfson
      - Erville Woods
      - Paul A. Witty
      - Austin B. Wood
      - Mary E. Woolley
    - Open letter, 1938 Feb. 4; 1p
      re Mrs. Bertha Edel
    - Open letter, 1938 Feb. 21; 2p
    - Open letter, 1938 Mar. 3; 1p
      enc. W. Routenstrauch to N.M. Butler
    - Outline for completion study: intermarriage & acculturation, 1938 Apr. 4; 2p
    - Completion of Study Poffenberger co-signed, 1938 Apr. 4; 2p
    - See H.C. Urey, 1938 Apr. 22
      - Co-signed: R.F. Benedict
      - I.H. Kaiser
      - H.C. Urey
      - L.C. Dunn
    - ?, 1938 May 12; 1p
    - Re E.A. Golomshtok, 1938 May 12; 1p
    - See Leo Frobenius (death card), 1938 Aug. 9
    - Studies, modern populations (see D. Young), 1938 Oct. 20
    - Circular letter, 1938 Nov.
    - Open letter
      - re Man & Paula Jacobs, 1938 Dec. 8; 1p
    - Open letter, 1938 Dec. 15; 1p
    - Anthrop. & modern life
      - see W.W. Norton Co., 1938 Dec.
    - Open letter
      - re E.M. Phelps (mrs. E.P. Hunt), 1939 Feb. 27; 1p
    - Draft, paper to American Assn. Sci. Workers?, 1939 Mar. 10; 6p
    - Open letter
      - re S.S. Newman, 1939 Mar. 13; 1p
    - See Jules Henry, 1939 Mar. 16
    - Notes for meeting, 1939 Mar. 17
    - Plan for mass meeting, 1939 Mar.
    - Open letter
      - FB, Honorary Pres.
      - Deutschamerikanischer
      - Kulturverband, 1939 Apr.; 1p
      - The Oregonian, 1939 July 19
    - Open letter
      - re M.S. Goldstein, 1939 July; 1p
      - re Henry Jules, 1939 July; 1p
    - List, birthday congratulations and newspaper clippings, 1939 July
    - Open letter
      - re S.S. Newman, 1934 July
    - Paper, modern population, 1934 July; 21p
      - co-signed by Gardner Murphy
      - F. Osborn
      - Otto Klineberg
      - F.J. Kallmann
    - Goodwin Watson H.L. Shapiro
    - Donald Young (enc. S. Theiss to B. Burks)
    - Book Rev., Revolution of Nihilism, 1939 Aug. 14; 1p
    - See B.J. Foss to S.L.M. Barlow, 1939 Sep. 28
    - Open letter, 1939 Dec.; 2p
      - Co-signed by Oliver LaFarge
      - E.B. Walling
      - W.C. Mitchell
      - D.O. Stewart
      - S.L.M. Barlow
      - Robt. Lynd
      - O.G. Villard
      - B.J. Foss
      - J.R. Walsh
    - Re Lawaune E. Kennard, 1939 Dec.; 1p
    - Statement to Science, 1939 Dec.; 1p
    - Report re American Commit. Democ. & Intellec. Freedom, 1939 Dec.; 5p
    - Open letter
      - re Morris Siegel, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p
    - Open letter re Mishkin, 1940 Feb. 5; 1p
    - Speech for Deutschamerikaner Kulturverband, 1940 Feb. 25; 6p
    - ?, 1940 May 6; 1p
    - Telegram, 1940 Mar
    - Open letter
      - re Ruth Landau, 1940 Mar. 8; 1p
      - re Wm. Lipkind, 1940 May 10; 1p